<article>
  <preamble>ACL2004-HEADLINE.txt</preamble>
  <titre>Hybrid Headlines: Combining Topics and Sentence Compression</titre>
  <auteur>     David Zajic, Bonnie Dorr, Stacy President         Richard Schwartz</auteur>
  <abstract>This paper presents Topiary, a headline- generation system that creates very short, informative summaries for news stories by combining sentence compres- sion and unsupervised topic discovery. We will show that the combination of linguistically motivated sentence com- pression with statistically selected topic terms performs better than either alone, according to some automatic summary evaluation measures. In addition we de- scribe experimental results establishing an appropriate extrinsic task on which to measure the effect of summarization on human performance. We demonstrate the usefulness of headlines in compar- ison to full texts in the context of this extrinsic task.</abstract>
  <biblio>Sabine Bergler, René Witte, Michelle Khalife,
Zhuoyan Li, and Frank Rudzicz. 2003. Using
knowledge-poor coreference resolution for text sum-
marization. In Proceedings of the 2003 Document
Understanding Conference, Draft Papers, pages 85–
92, Edmonton, Candada.
Bonnie Dorr, David Zajic, and Richard Schwartz.
2003a. Cross-language headline generation for
hindi. ACM Transactions on Asian Language Infor-      Liang Zhou and Eduard Hovy. 2003. Headline sum-
mation Processing (TALIP), 2:2.
Bonnie Dorr, David Zajic, and Richard Schwartz.
2003b. Hedge trimmer: A parse-and-trim approach
to headline generation. In Proceedings of the HLT-
NAACL 2003 Text Summarization Workshop, Ed-
monton, Alberta, Canada, pages 1–8.
T. Euler. 2002. Tailoring text using topic words: Se-
lection and compression. In Proceedings of 13th
International Workshop on Database and Expert
Systems Applications (DEXA 2002), 2-6 Septem-
ber 2002, Aix-en-Provence, France, pages 215–222.
IEEE Computer Society.
Kevin Knight and Daniel Marcu. 2000. Statistics-
based summarization – step one: Sentence com-
pression. In The 17th National Conference of</biblio>
  <conclusion>in speed. Subjects spent an average of 30 seconds per document when shown the entire text, but only      We have shown the effectiveness of combining 7.7 seconds per document when shown the head-          sentence compression and topic lists to construct line. Table 4 shows the precision, recall and        informative summaries. We have compared three approaches to automatic headline generation (Top-         the American Association for Artificial Intelligence iary, Hedge Trimmer and Unsupervised Topic Dis-           AAAI2000, Austin, Texas. covery) using two automatic summarization evalu-        David Lewis. 1992. An evaluation of phrasal and clus- ation tools (BLEU and ROUGE). We have stressed            tered representations on a text categorization task. the importance of correlating automatic evalua-           In Proceedings of the 15th annual international tions with human performance of an extrinsic task,        ACM SIGIR conference on Research and develop-                                                           ment in information retrieval, pages 37–50, Copen- and have proposed event tracking as an appropri-          hagen, Denmark. ate task for this purpose.    We plan to perform a study in which Topiary,         Chin-Yew Lin and Eduard Hovy. 2003. Auto-                                                           matic Evaluation of Summaries Using N-gram Co- Hedge Trimmer, Unsupervised Topic Discovery               Occurrences Statistics. In Proceedings of the Con- and other summarization methods will be evalu-            ference of the North American Chapter of the As- ated in the context of event tracking. We also plan       sociation for Computational Linguistics, Edmonton, to extend the tools described in this paper to the        Alberta. domains of transcribed broadcast news and cross-        Ingrid Mårdh. 1980. Headlinese: On the Grammar of language headline generation.                              English Front Page Headlines. Malmo. Acknowledgements                                        S. Miller, M. Crystal, H. Fox, L. Ramshaw,                                                           R. Schwartz, R. Stone, and R. Weischedel. 1998. The University of Maryland authors are sup-               Algorithms that Learn to Extract Information; BBN:                                                           Description of the SIFT System as Used for MUC-7. ported, in part, by BBNT Contract 020124-                 In Proceedings of the MUC-7. 7157, DARPA/ITO Contract N66001-97-C-8540, and NSF CISE Research Infrastructure Award              K. Papineni, S. Roukos, T. Ward, and W. Zhu. 2002.                                                           Bleu: a Method for Automatic Evaluation of Ma- EIA0130422.                                                           chine Translation. In Proceedings of Association of                                                           Computational Linguistics, Philadelphia, PA.</conclusion>
</article>
