<article>
  <preamble>hybrid_approach.txt</preamble>
  <titre>Sentence Compression for Automated Subtitling: A Hybrid Approach</titre>
  <auteur>                                    Maria Theresiastraat 21</auteur>
  <abstract>In this paper a sentence compression tool is de- scribed. We describe how an input sentence gets analysed by using a.o. a tagger, a shallow parser and a subordinate clause detector, and how, based on this analysis, several compressed versions of this sentence are generated, each with an associated es- timated probability. These probabilities were esti- mated from a parallel transcript/subtitle corpus. To avoid ungrammatical sentences, the tool also makes use of a number of rules. The evaluation was done on three different pronunciation speeds, averaging sentence reduction rates of 40% to 17%. The num- ber of reasonable reductions ranges between 32.9% and 51%, depending on the average estimated pro- nunciation speed.</abstract>
  <biblio>G. Booij and A. van Santen. 1995. Morfologie. De
woordstructuur van het Nederlands. Amsterdam
University Press, Amsterdam, Netherlands.
T. Brants. 2000. TnT - A Statistical Part-of-Speech
Tagger. Published online at http://www.coli.uni-
sb.de/thorsten/tnt.
W. Daelemans and H. Strik. 2002. Het Neder-
lands in Taal- en Spraaktechnologie: Prioriteiten
voor Basisvoorzieningen. Technical report, Ne-
derlandse Taalunie.
B. Dewulf and G. Saerens. 2000. Stijlboek
Teletekst Ondertiteling. Technical report, VRT,
Brussel. Internal Subtitling Guidelines.
W. Haeseryn, G. Geerts, J de Rooij, and
M. van den Toorn. 1997. Algemene Neder-
landse Spraakkunst. Martinus Nijhoff Uitgevers,
Groningen.</biblio>
  <conclusion>alternative which was shorter than the maximum           We have described a hybrid approach to sentence    number of characters available for that sentence.        compression which seems to work in general. The    The cases where no output is generated are not con-      combination of using statistics and filtering out in-    sidered as errors because it is often impossible, even   valid results because they are ungrammatical by us-    for humans, to reduce a sentence by about 40%,           ing a set of rules is a feasible way for automated sentence compression.                                   ITC.       1997.        Guidance on standards    The way of combining the probability-estimates          for     subtitling.         Technical       report, of chunk removal to get a ranking in the generated         ITC.        Online at http://www.itc.org.uk/ sentence alternatives is working reasonably well,          codes guidelines/broadcasting/tv/sub sign but could be improved by using more fine-grained            audio/subtitling stnds/. chunk types for data collection.                        H. Jing. 2001. Cut-and-Paste Text Summarization.    A full syntactic analysis of the input sentence         Ph.D. thesis, Columbia University. would lead to better results, as the current sentence   F.J. Koopmans-van Beinum and M.E. van Donzel. analysis tools have one very weak point: the han-          1996. Relationship Between Discourse Structure dling of coordinating conjunction, which leads to          and Dynamic Speech Rate. In Proceedings IC- chunking errors, both in the input sentence as in the      SLP 1996, Philadelphia, USA. processing of the used parallel corpus. This leads to   N. Oostdijk, W. Goedertier, F. Van Eynde, L. Boves, misestimations of the compression probabilities and        J.P. Marters, M. Moortgat, and H. Baayen. 2002. creates noise in the behaviour of our system.              Experiences from the Spoken Dutch Corpus. In    Making use of semantics would most probably             Proceedings of LREC 2002, volume I, pages 340– lead to better results, but a semantic lexicon and         347, Paris. ELRA. semantic analysis tools are not available for Dutch,    F. Van Eynde. 2004. Part-of-speech Tagging and creating them would be out of the scope of the         en Lemmatisering. Internal manual of Cor- current project.                                           pus Gesproken Nederlands, published online at    In future research we will check the effects of         http://www.ccl.kuleuven.ac.be/Papers/ improved word-reduction modules, as word reduc-            POSmanual febr2004.pdf. tions often seem to lead to inaccurate compres-         V. Vandeghinste and E. Tjong Kim Sang. 2004. Us- sions. Leaving out the word-reduction module               ing a parallel transcript/subtitle corpus for sen- would probably lead to an even bigger amount of            tence compression. In Proceedings of LREC no output-cases. This will also be checked in future       2004, Paris. ELRA. research.                                               V. Vandeghinste. 2002. Lexicon optimization:                                                            Maximizing lexical coverage in speech recogni- 5 Acknowledgements                                         tion through automated compounding. In Pro- Research funded by IWT (Institute for Innovation           ceedings of LREC 2002, volume IV, pages 1270– in Science and Technology) in the STWW pro-                1276, Paris. ELRA. gram, project ATraNoS (Automatic Transcription          V. Vandeghinste. submitted. ShaRPa: Shallow and Normalisation of Speech). For more informa-            Rule-based Parsing, focused on Dutch. In Pro- tion visit http://atranos.esat.kuleuven.ac.be/.            ceedings of CLIN 2003.    We would like to thank Ineke Schuurman for rat- ing the reduced sentences.</conclusion>
</article>
